Okay, let's talk about a few common tools
used to track performance of your work.
So performance tracking and we'll talk
about a couple of reports as well.
Now one of the tools I'm going to talk
about is this one called the Canban Board.
And in fact, we actually have a separate
video on Canban boards.
So we'll talk about canban boards
separately in the separate video.
But it is a performance tracking tool.
So that's why we wanted to mention it
here.
Now another tool that you might use is
something known as a throughput metrics
and a throughput metric basically
calculates you know the amount of work
that the team has done over time right so
it basically for example the average
number of tasks that are being completed
in a week right or you know the number of
tasks that we performed you know in an
iteration for example right so that's what
throughput metric refers to right the
calculation of the team's work right the
entire work performed by the team over a
particular period of time Cycle time,
right, is a term that's
basically looking at
the progression of the
work from start to end.
So, how long has it taken from
the time the work was actually
started to the work it was,
to the time it was finished?
Right, how long has that time taken?
Essentially, how long has it been a
working process or a work in progress?
So it's going to include, for example,
stoppage time, like, so you stop this
activity, and then you start
working on something else,
and you come back to this
one, come back to this activity.
It's not looking at the level of effort
that it's taken.
It's looking at the
entire time, including,
like I said, including the stoppage time.
We started on this date, we finished it on
this date.
Now, in between, we might have been
working on other things as well,
so we weren't working 100% on this
particular activity, but how long has it
taken to basically complete that activity
from start to finish?
That's what the cycle time refers to.
How long it's been actually a work in
progress?
Then you'll come across this term here
called earned value.
Earned value are those formulas that we've
covered in the cost management section.
So schedule variance, cost variance,
all of those.
So earned value is essentially showing you
the health of a project.
And you'll be creating earned value
reports.
So all of the metrics
from the earned value
calculations, You might
create them in a report.
A Gant chart is another type of report,
another type of performance report looking
at the schedule, whereas earned value is
generally looking at cost.
But of course, you've got a schedule variance
as well, which looks at the schedule.
But the Gant chart is purely and simply
looking at the schedule, right,
progress of your schedule.
Now, this other term then, you might come
across this term called velocity,
which refers to the total speed of an
iteration or the total speed of an activity.
And what velocity really is looking at is
the amount of completed level of effort,
how long this activity has taken in terms
of level of effort, such as man hours,
for example.
So that's what velocity is referring to.
Right now, it sounds very similar to
throughput.
So in the previous slide, we talked about
throughput metric, right?
So velocity sounds very similar,
but the basic difference is with
throughput, throughput
metrics, it's looking at
actual number of tasks
that have been completed.
over time, whereas velocity is looking at
more of the level of effort that's been
taken over time, such as, you know,
hours, level of effort in terms of hours,
man hours, and so and so forth.
Then a couple of other reports,
right, you might come across this one
called the Quality Report, and this
obviously is looking at the quality,
right, so tracking defects and accepted
deliverables and so on and so forth.
And then you have this term called Value
Streamer Now, value
stream map is more of a lean.
Some of that's using lean technique.
It's a type of flow chart.
It's basically used for process
improvement.
Identifying inefficiencies.
Inefficiencies in the process.
For example, in a
manufacturing environment,
you have your raw
materials that are delivered.
These raw materials now go through several
processes before it gets
delivered to the customer.
So what are all the steps involved?
So in a flowchart, you'll
show all the steps involved
from this raw material
being delivered to you, right?
Once we've received the raw materials,
all the different steps involved in order
to create the final product when it's
shipped out to the customer.
So the value stream map then is going to
show all of the different procedures.
different processes and then from there
you can see which processes need to be
improved right which processes where are
we finding bottlenecks and inefficiencies
that can be proved about right and then
each process then is going to be
identifying how long it's taking this
process how long does this process take
process B how long will that take and then
you know do we have any downtime that says
some downtime before we start process C
and so and so and so forth right so it's
going to include then leads and lags and
so and so forth so so value stream map
then is looking at the whole process from
start to end and then you're trying to
identify inefficiencies to improve
processes okay so these are just a couple
of the common tools and
reports when it comes to
performance right performance
tracking and reporting